One problem that can come up with switches
is that loops can occur.
They can be physical, such as when a device
is plugged into itself by accident, which
can cause what is known as a broadcast storm,
in that broadcasts flood through a switch,
eventually overloading it.
If not physical, switches are prone to receiving
multiple copies of the same frame of data
as it goes through a network.
Switches should have a protocol called Spanning
Tree Protocol enabled to combat this.
STP, as it is known, when enabled, uses a
spanning-tree algorithm, known as STA, to
search for, find, and then destroy redundant
links.
Links are found by transmitting BPDUs, Bridge
Protocol Data Units, and then once a redundant
link is identified, it is destroyed.